Guide to the Office of the Provost, Finance and Administration Records, 1987-2016 UA.05.01.0051
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Office of the Provost, Finance and Administration Records
1987-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of the Provost. Finance and Administration
UA.05.01.0051
15 Linear Feet
The Finance and Administration group is a part of the Office of the Provost of Duke University responsible for budgets and cost planning of all academic and administrative units under the Provost, as well as human resources, space planning, and the university's support of Duke Kunshan University. The collection includes materials related to planning and opening of Duke Kunshan University, student financial aid, and other topics.
Biographical / Historical
The Finance and Administration group is a part of the Office of the Provost of Duke University. Finance and Administration is responsible for coordinating the budgets, cost allocations, and budget reporting of academic and administrative units under the Provost; administering human resources for all areas under the Provost; facilitating Duke's global activities, including support of Duke Kunshan University; managing the administration of student and faculty technology systems; and facilitating space planning and allocation, among other activities. Offices and groups that report to Finance and Administration include Budget and Finance, the Duke Kunshan University Support Unit, Human Resources, Faculty Affairs and Records, and Institutional Research.
James S. Roberts is the Executive Vice Provost for Finance and Administration and has been in the Office of the Provost since the mid-1990s.
Sources: Office of the Provost, Finance and Administration website, https://finance.provost.duke.edu/, viewed 2017 August 01.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Office of the Provost, Finance and Administration Records were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in 2017 and 2019.
Related Materials
Office of the Provost: John Strohbehn Records, 1994-1999, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Office of the Provost, Peter Lange Records 1999-2014, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Collection Overview
Includes materials related to planning, construction, and opening of Duke Kunshan University; planning and reporting related to student financial aid; university strategic planning; and other topics. The collection has not yet been processed.
Conditions Governing Access
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Conditions Governing Access
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Conditions Governing Access
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Student financial aid administration -- North Carolina -- Durham; Universities and colleges -- Planning; Duke University. Office of the Provost. Finance and Administration; Duke Kunshan University
- Accession UA2017-0035, 1987-2016; 1
  - DKU program marketing strategies & budget reports, undated (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until 2040
  - Kunshan resource docs, undated (Box 1)
  - 2011 China Trip (Box 1)
    Restricted until 2036
  - DKU construction issues 2011 (Box 1)
  - AOA of DKU 2011 (Box 1)
  - Materials from University Counsel, undated (Box 1)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 1)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 1)
  - JR 127 Allen, undated (Box 1)
  - B&F Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - Legal, undated (Box 1)
  - Planning guide, undated (Box 1)
  - Greg Jones, undated (Box 1)
  - HR, undated (Box 1)
  - Fuquas entry into Chinese Market, undated (Box 2)
  - DKU Market Research, undated (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 2)
  - School Services & Regulations, undated (Box 2)
  - Chinese Regulations, undated (Box 2)
  - Medial Physics, undated (Box 2)
  - Above Undergrad, undated (Box 2)
  - Undergraduate programs, undated (Box 2)
  - Global Health, undated (Box 2)
  - Financial Planning, undated (Box 2)
  - Legal Advice, undated (Box 2)
  - Executive Prep Committee, undated (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 2)
  - DKU Overview of financial modeling, undated (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 2)
  - 2011 Fin Planning (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 2)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 2)
  - China Trip Jan 4-12 2012, 2012 January 04 - 2012 January 12 (Box 3)
    Restricted until 2037
  - SACS DKU, undated (Box 3)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 3)
  - Duke International Policys 2012 (Box 3)
  - China Trip 10/27-11/3 2012, 2012 October 27 - 2012 November 3 (Box 3)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 3)
  - DKU Phase 2 Final Agreements, undated (Box 3)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 3)
  - China Trip 4/11-17 2015, 2015 April 11 - 2015 April 17 (Box 3)
  - May 2016 DKU Trip, 2016 May (Box 3)
    Restricted until 2041
  - Tuition Memo Financial Projection English, undated (Box 3)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 3)
  - Director of Financial Aid Review 3/14/03, 2003 March 14 (Box 4)
    Restricted until 2028
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 4)
  - Duke External Review Visit- UG Admissions & Fin Aid 2/6-8 2008, 2008 February 06 - 2008 February 08 (Box 4)
    Restricted until 2033
  - Consultancy Sept 1996 (Box 4)
    Restricted until 2021
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 4)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 4)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 4)
  - GDA Integrated Services DEHNE November 2010 (Box 5)
    Restricted until 2035
  - 2011 College Boards admitted students survey (Box 5)
  - DEHNE Report 2003 (Box 5)
  - Financial Aid Initiative Fall 2015 (Box 5)
  - Background Data on Undergraduate Aid Initiative 2007 (Box 5)
    Restricted until 2032
  - Fin Aid Notes 04/05, 2004-2005 (Box 5)
    Restricted until 2030
  - BoT Financial Aid Materials September 2005, 2005 September (Box 5)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 5)
  - Financial Aid- Award Budget FY 06/07, 2006-2007 (Box 5)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 5)
  - College Board 2004 Report (Box 5)
    Restricted until 2029
  - Financial Aid Strategic Planning Committee, undated (Box 5)
  - Financial Aid Planning Committee, undated (Box 5)
  - Aid/ Admissions Analysis FY 02/03, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
  - Engaging in Educational Activities in China and Higher Education and Foreign Schools in China, undated (Box 6)
  - Office of Global Strategy & Programs DKU Financial Projections, undated (Box 6)
  - A Common Approach to Need Analysis- The 568 President's Group Oct 2002, 2002 October (Box 7)
    Restricted until 2027
  - DEHNE Report September 2003, 2003 September (Box 7)
  - 2006 College Board Tuition and Financial Aid Reports (Box 7)
    Restricted until 2031
  - 2006 Aid- Yield Studies (Box 7)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate Financial Aid Baseline Report, undated (Box 8)
  - Undergraduate Financial Aid Baseline Report, undated (Box 8)
  - Presidents Book Financial Aid- Cofhe annual meeting december 2010, 2010 December (Box 8)
  - Paying for college 2007 Parents Survey (Box 8)
  - 2008 Trends in Higher Education Series (Box 8)
  - 568 antitrust expemption, undated (Box 8)
  - Financial Aid Trends & Implications for COFHE Instituions, undated (Box 8)
  - Exploring Student Aig Impacts on College Experiences December 2003, 2003 December (Box 8)
  - Financial Aid at Duke University, undated (Box 8)
  - 2007 Trends in College Pricing & Student Aid (Box 8)
  - Breifing Materials UG Fin Aid 9/24/2004, 2004 September 24 (Box 8)
  - COFHE Presidents Book 2004/2005 (Box 8)
  - 2006 Planning Process (Box 9)
  - BoT Afternoon Session Financial Challenges Feb 27 2009, 2009 February 07 (Box 9)
    Restricted until 2034
  - Planning Progress Report Feb 15 2000, 2000 February 15 (Box 9)
    Restricted until 2025
  - Shaping Our Future, undated (Box 9)
  - 1987 Plan (Box 9)
  - A Duke Plan, undated (Box 9)
  - 1994 Plan (Box 9)
  - 1992 School Plans (Box 9)
  - Duke University- Report on Graduate Education, undated (Box 9)
  - Academic Plan Duke University- Working Draft, undated (Box 9)
  - Board of Trustees Retreat, 2006 February 24 - 2006 February 25 (Box 9)
    Restricted until 2056
  - Building on Excellence- The University Plan, undated (Box 9)
  - Unfoldered Materials, undated (Box 10)
  - 1992 School Plans (Box 10)
  - Duke Finance Retreat Feb 7 2009, 2009 February 07 (Box 10)
  - Strategic Planning Binder 2006-2011 Binder 1 (Box 10)
  - Strategic Planning Binder 2006-2011 Binder 2 (Box 10)
  - Board of Trustees Retreat, 2005 February 25 - 2005 February 26 (Box 10)
    Restricted until 2055
  - Making a Difference: The Strategic Plan for Duke University 9/29/06, 2006 September 29 (Box 10)
- Accession UA2019.0053, 1980-2019
  - James S. Roberts Journals/Notes: DKU, circa 2010s; 5 items (Box 11)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2044.
  - Duke Kunshan (DKU) student information systems planning notebook, December 2016; 3 items (Box 11)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2041.
  - Business and Finance Committee Meeting Memo docs, 2010-2013 (Box 11)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2038.
  - DKU Cooperative Agreement Wuhan Univ., 2013 (Box 11)
  - DKU signed legal documents, circa 2010s (Box 11)
  - DKU formal establishment application, circa 2010s (Box 11)
  - High Education-China Ed Laws, June 2014 (Box 11)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2039.
  - DKU Committee Memos and Docs, 2010-2013 (Box 11)
  - DKU Partner's Update-DKU Financial Production, April 2003 (Box 12)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2028.
  - James S. Roberts: Emails on Financial Aid, 2018 (Box 12)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2033.
  - James S. Roberts: Affordability Trustees Committee, February 11, 2019 (Box 12)
  - James S. Roberts: Undergraduate Financial Aid Docs, 2017 (Box 12)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2042.
  - James S. Roberts: Undergraduate Financial Aid Docs, 2018 (Box 12)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2043.
  - James S. Roberts: Undergraduate Financial Aid Docs, 2016 (Box 12)
  - James S. Roberts: Undergraduate Financial Aid Docs, 2013 (Box 12)
  - James S. Roberts: Undergraduate Financial Aid Docs, 2003-2004 (Box 12)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2029.
  - James S. Roberts: Undergraduate Financial Aid Docs, 1980-1998 (Box 12)
    Administrative materials restricted until 2023.
  - James S. Roberts: DKU Materials, 1980-2019 (Box 13)
  - James S. Roberts: Assorted Materials, 1980-2019 (Box 13)
  - James S. Roberts: Assorted Materials, 1980-2019 (Box 14)